In Sicily, you stand by the law or by the Mafia. Only
one man ever dared to stand alone.
The Sicilian is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by Michael Cimino.
Egocentric bandit Salvatore Giuliano fights the Church, the Mafia, and the landed
gentry while leading a populist movement for Sicilian independence.
Salvatore Giuliano, played by Christopher Lambert.
Prince Borsa, played by Terence Stamp.
Don Masino Croce, played by Joss Ackland.
Pisciotta, played by John Turturro.
Hector Adonis, played by Richard Bauer.
Camilla, Duchess of Crotone, played by Barbara Sukowa.
The Sicilian is a 1987 epic historical crime film directed by Michael Cimino.
The film was adapted by Steve Shagan, and later rewritten by Cimino and
Gore Vidal from Mario Puzo's 1984 novel of the same name.
Christopher Lambert stars as Salvatore Giuliano, the infamous bandit who
tried to liberate early 1950s Sicily from Italian rule.
The film also stars Terence Stamp, Joss Ackland,
John Turturro and Barbara Sukowa.
The film explores themes of sicily, italy, sicilian mafia, sicilian.
The tone is emotional and intense.